David Padilla

Full Stack Web Developer

Portfolio davidpadilla.io GitHub github.com/dpadillajs

Advanced experience in creating the perfect UX/UI design alongside server-based operations using both relational and non-relational databases. Over 700+ contributions on GitHub building full stack web applications with goals to solve the individual needs of users today.

Successful in working both team and self-directed settings to meet coding project deadlines. Proven ability to quickly master new technologies.

Personal Info

Phone

+1 919 869 9647

Email

davidpadilla.dev@gmail.com

Address

Raleigh, NC 27615

Technical Skills

FRONT END TECHNOLOGIES

HTML5

CSS3

Bootstrap 4

Material-UI

JavaScript

ES6

jQuery

Handlebars

Firebase

React

BACK END TECHNOLOGIES

Node.js

Express

NoSQL

MongoDB

Mongoose

MySQL

Sequelize

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES

RESTful APIs

MVC Architecture

JSON

AJAX

Debugging Tools

Project Experience

2019-04

Recipedia

Full Stack Web Developer

Recipedia is a MERN-stack application that makes weekly meal planning easier. Designed with the busy professional in mind, the site allows users to search for recipes, favorite them for future reference, and build a weekly menu.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Created authentication with **Firebase** so that users can signup as a registered member or demo the application with limited features as an anonymous guest.
- Formulated **API** calls within a **NodeJS** development environment using **MongoDB** queries to allow the user to search for recipes with filtering options.
- Designed multiple webpages using **Material-UI** as a component library for **React**.

https://my-recipedia.com/

2019-03

Personal Portfolio

Front-end Web Developer

My personal portfolio is the culmination of some of my best work that's stylized in a sleek modern web design made from scratch. Mobile responsiveness across all devices with optimization for viewport widths as small as 320px.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Integrated multiple **jQuery** plugins with **HTML** and **CSS** alterations to match the visual identity of the website.
- Investigated bugs using **DevTools** to deliver synchronous code solutions caused by the limitations of **jQuery**'s rendering speed.
- Utilized Bootstrap and media queries to deliver responsiveness to mobile devices.

https://www.davidpadilla.io/

2019-02

Gamelogger

Full Stack Web Developer

Gamelogger is a full stack application that allows gamers to keep track of their videogames in progress. Gamers can then go back to mark them as completed once they're finished saving the world.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Constructed a data model for MySQL operations to exist for managing videogames.
- Simplified database queries using **Sequelize** as an object-relational mapper from open source software (**NPM**).
- Improved readability of code by following an MVC Architecture for folder structuring and using Handlebars for semantic templating.

https://gamelogger-app.herokuapp.com/



Education

2018-10 -

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Coding Boot Camp - Full Stack Web Development Certification

2019-04

An intensive 24 week program dedicated to building full stack web applications.